Julianne Van Wagenenjvanwagenen.github.io | Cambridge, MA, USA | +1 517 505 5057 | jmvanwag@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Graduate-level program and content manager; ex-university instructor; researcher; webmaster; project manager; & book/journal managing editor; detail-oriented self-starter who enjoys and excels at problem solving in a team environment; 15+ years experience in web design & ed program creation/coordination

SKILLS

Interpersonal Communication Team building & Collaboration Academic Research and Writing Attention to Detail

Project Management Strategic & Organizational Planning Meaningful Goal-driven Content Creation **Problem Solving**

Qualitative & Quantitative Research Presentations & Public Speaking Adobe Suite, HTML, CSS Foreign Languages

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

HBS Online, Harvard Business Analytics Program

Online Learning Manager

Boston, MA

July 2022 - Present

- Manage courses and seminars on the online course platform, which includes: liaising with faculty and TFs, updating course content, coordinating live sessions, office hours, and simulations across the term, managing the courses in Slack
- Act as the accessibility lead for HBAP, which includes remediating videos and slide decks, creating Audio Descriptions and Elaborated Transcripts, and working with 2U to implement all updates on in the online courses
- Create videos using Premiere as needed, most recently for social media and the Digital Campus Orientation Course
- Create and manage much of the supplemental programming HBAP offers, including: Startup Academy 8-week online course (2023; created with a team and executed); Pitch Competition, which includes a mentor series, pitch workshops, the submission round, live online finals, and an (2023-24; updated and executed); Summer Programming (2023-24; created and executed); Spring Career Services webinar series (2024; updated and executed); D^3 Cubie Awards and Ceremony (2024; worked with a team to create and execute on a short timeline)
- Work with a team to plan and execute our in-person immersions three times a year

Harvard University Postdoctoral Fellow

Cambridge, MA January 2022 - July 2022

- Book project proposal selected from a wide group of candidates from around the world
- Work on research and publishing related to countercultural song, modern mythologies, mass tourism, and travel ethics; have published and peer-reviewed book and articles (see below).

Pirandello in Translation - Stories for a Year

Web Developer, Translator (pirandellointranslation.org)

2021 - Present

- Designed and built the book-project website, which hosts a growing number of original translations of Luigi Pirandello
- Worked with a team to create project goals wire-frame design, take feedback, and work to consensus on final build out Continue to work with a team to coordinate the translation and presentation of digital publication of new translations
- Pirandello Society of America

Board of Directors

2019 - Present

- Help organize the scheduling and program-details for our quarterly board-member meetings
- Present and lead discussions: such topics as moving general membership payment online; website renovation; new website design; updating membership policies and costs; hosting our journal archive online; organizing annual events
- Work with content editors to clearly communicate complex issues and reach consensus amongst board members
- Work with content editors to elaborate and enact the steps of all society projects from inception to delivery (new membership payment system; digital archive; annual journal production; printing costs and new printing options; etc.)

Pirandello Society of America

Web Developer (pirandellosociety.org)

- Designed and built the literary-society and academic-journal website
- Worked with a team to create project goals wire-frame design, take feedback, and work to consensus on final build out
- Continue to work with a team to coordinate website updates

The Pirandello Society Annual Journal

Managing Editor

2017 - 2023

- Design and build each the annual journal using InDesign; create cover designs in Gimp
- Copy-edit the content and formatting for the entire journal
- Work with the content editors to come to a consensus on cover design and other formatting questions
- Prepare journal for printer; communicate with printer across the entire process to assure print accuracy

Tsinghua University

Beijing, China

Fall 2018 - Fall 2021

- Instructor, Thesis Advisor Designed and taught 3 courses in the Institute of World Literatures and Cultures (IWLC): "Journey to Italy: Travel Writing since the Grand Tour", "Rereading the Divine Comedy with Borges", "Postcolonial Literature across the 1900s"
 - Instituted an initiative in sophomore seminars that helped students to excel in academic writing

- Helped organize the curriculum of IWLC in terms of pedagogical and content goals and continuity across semesters
- Organized a Graduate School Application workshop; organized workshops, mentored students one-on-one
- Advised senior-theses; organized time, set small deliverable dates; advised on research, citational styles, clarity of writing

University of Southern California

Lecturer

Los Angeles, CA Spring 2018

- Taught 3 courses in Italian language, worked with a team to create and grade bi-weekly assessments
- Worked with a team to create a community-based component to the language courses; facilitated weekly language table

Milan and Siena: Harvard Summer School Study Abroad

Milan and Siena, Italy

Coordinator, Instructor Summer 2016, Summer 2017

- Worked with another coordinator to develop and teach the language-program courses for a new study-abroad program - Worked with a team to organize the housing, field trips, events, reservations for a group of 30 undergraduates
- Led 2 sections of 8-credit Aesthetics & Ethics course taught during the summer abroad
- Handled all translation, documentation, and emergency issues for study-abroad students

Monad Media

Owner, Project Manager

Cambridge, MA 2014 - 2017

- Founded company that provided economical web development to academic projects
- Worked with creative teams in Harvard GSAS and Libraries to create wire frames and present ideas to my developers
- Led project management, including timelines, deadlines, cost analysis, bug fixes, etc., for all projects

metaLAB (at) Harvard

Cambridge, MA 2013 – 2017

Project Manager, Principal Investigator

- Participated as a creative lead in metaLAB principal meetings; wrote grant applications for various projects
- Worked with a team of professors to create interdisciplinary courses (offered FAS and GSD); created syllabi, created and taught innovate discussion-sections/studios; organized summer developer workshops and new digital-humanities projects
- Project manager for curarium.com; managed 3 to 4 developers using Redmine, reported timelines and progress to advisors at the Berkman Klein Center, tracked deadlines and bug fixes, presented platform at conferences and workshops

Harvard University Cambridge, MA

Course Developer, Instructor, Thesis Advisor

2013 - 2017

- Developed and taught courses in language and literature in the Romance Languages and Literatures department
- Wrote grant applications; won 2017 Elson Family Arts Initiative Fund to Support the Integration of Arts into Curriculum
- Won the Harvard University Department of Romance Languages and Literatures Teaching Prize in 2016
- Won the Derek Bok Center for Teaching and Learning Certificate of Excellence for every semester I was eligible
- Organized Chiasmi Graduate Student Conference in 2013
- Presented at panels or invited talks and/or organized and chaired panels at over 20 conferences and events

Dudley House Library Cambridge, MA Head Librarian 2012 - 2017

- Hired and managed a team of between 5 and 8 librarians
- Wrote schedules and handled all scheduling changes and emergencies

Harvard University Cambridge, MA Doctoral Researcher 2011 - 2017

- Completed my doctoral work on time and with a successful dissertation that has been recently contracted for publication
- Assistant to the departmental chair in 2016; edited departmental correspondence, helped schedule, took minutes
- 2013-14 Video Coordinator for Colloquium Speaker series; coordinated and helped edit production of video interviews
- Copy-edited various projects, for example, Johanna Drucker's Graphesis (2014)
- Worked as a translator for the Italian cantautori in Translation website theitaliansong.com

The American in Italia Magazine

Rome, Italy

Columnist

2009 - 2014

Roma, Italy

- Met monthly deadlines, worked with editor to revise, copy edit; published over 40 articles that are still available online

Physical Chemistry Department, Michigan State University

East Lansing, MI

- Web Developer, Data Analyst
 - Created a website (Dreamweaver) for the PI's research project on the dipole moment of white-dwarf stars
 - Wrote programs in Terminal that ran on the university super computer and simulated how molecules would act when put under the intense atmospheric pressure of a white-dwarf star; collected and organized all data after program runs

EDUCATION

Harvard University - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences

Cambridge, MA

PhD, Italian Studies

September 2011 - May 2017

DePaul University - Honors College

Chicago, IL

BA, with High Honors, Double Major in Italian Studies and English Literature

September 2002 - March 2006

Additional Study

September 2007 - June 2008

L'università Roma Tre, Biology Program

LANGUAGES

English (native), Italian (near-native), Spanish (intermediate), French (basic)

SOFTWARE

Adobe Creative Suite (Premiere, Express, Dreamweaver, InDesign, Photoshop (Gimp)); Canvas; Redmine; Excel; Atom (HTML and CSS); GitHub

MEDIA COVERAGE

Research Featured in Volpe, Andrea. "Being Human Now: How Innovative Methods and Contemporary Concerns are Helping Humanities Scholars Re-Envision the Past and Imagine the Future." Colloquy. Spring 2016. 12-17.